Underneath the blue, blue sky,
amongst the soft grass of the riverbank,
let's play a game of hide and seek,
in the midst of the sunflower fields.
Let's send a soap bubble to the sky.
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday,
your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
Chase after those white, white clouds.
...The Organ Boy's Day.
Run, run...
You've been energetic all morning even though it's terribly hot.
What song is that?
It's one I learned from Yomogi Nursery!
It's such a fun song, isn't it?
From the top of the great mountains-
That scared me!
I thought I was going to fall.
You're too loud!
Oh! Good morning!
What are you doing this early on a Sunday morning?
A-Airing out the futon! Seeing how it's so nice out today and all...
Can't you do anything without causing such a commotion?
Bully.
Do-ba-to!
Ioryogi! Are you okay?
"Are you okay"?!
I told you didn't I?!
I'm a stuffed animal right now!
I can't be doing things like that!
I'm sorry!
I'm off.
Have a safe trip.
Thanks.
Chitose just said goodbye to Fujimoto, right?
Obviously.
That's strange.
What?
When I was talking to him, he was next door. Now he's already out the door.
He's a busy guy.
What if...
There are two Fujimotos?
This isn't a mystery story!!
Kobato?
What was that sound?
N-Nothing!
Where are you going?
Yomogi Nursery.
But you have today off, don't you?
I'm going to go air out the futons for them because it's such a nice day!
Kobato, do you really understand?
Understand what?
Why you're here.
In order to fill up the bottle with konpeito!
Since you understand, don't you think you have other things that you should be doing today?
But...
For now, I want to try and help Yomogi Nursery. Even if I can only help a little.
Reporting!
Apparently the previous head of Yomogi Nursery was tricked and forced to borrow a lot of money.
The previous head?
Sayaka Okiura's father. He passed away two years ago or something like that.
The ones who tricked him were pretty dangerous guys,
and now they're harassing Sayaka Okiura as well.
Miss Sayaka!
Kobato?
What's the matter? We're not open today.
I know, but I came to air out the futons.
The futons?
Yes! The weather is just perfect for it today.
It really is a nice day out today...
I totally didn't notice.
All right then. Let's air them out together.
Okay!
Chitose's really glad she managed to get such a good tenant like you to stay at her place, Kobato.
I'm really glad things worked out too!
It's so much fun to be with Chitose, Chiho and Chise!
How about Fujimoto?
Has he been... picking on you?
Fujimoto does pick on me sometimes...
But there are times he doesn't...
I don't really understand.
I don't understand what
kind of person Fujimoto is.
He might not look like it,
but Fujimoto's a nice person.
He's always been like that, even when he was little.
Little Fujimoto?
I can't imagine that...
Would you like to see?
Sorry for the wait!
I found them.
Here you go.
He's so little!
Is this really Fujimoto?
Yup. This picture was taken on
Fujimoto's first day at the nursery.
Fujimoto was a student here before?
No, it's not that.
Fujimoto was...
An orphan.
An orphan? What does orphan mean?
A child who doesn't have a father or mother or family anymore.
If you don't have the resolve to see it all the way through, don't get involved.
If you're just showing that you care about him for your own self-satisfaction,
then you're the same as the owner who abandoned him.
So that's why...
...he said stuff like that.
Kobato?
Please tell me!
I want to know more about Fujimoto as a child!
All right.
I think it's already been
fourteen years since then...
Since my father took in Fujimoto.
Sayaka, I'm home.
This is the child I was talking about before, Kiyokazu Fujimoto.
Kiyokazu, this is my daughter, Sayaka.
I'm Sayaka. It's nice to meet you, Kiyokazu.
T-That's right! Let's take a picture to commemorate this day, okay?
I'll go get the camera.
Camera, camera, where is it...
Here we go.
Say Yomogi Nursery!
Fujimoto's been living here ever since then.
He looks like he's angry in this picture.
When he first came here,
he always looked like that.
He wouldn't speak to anyone.
Not even you, Miss Sayaka?
Even me. He was always by himself...
I even introduced him to the children.
In the beginning, everyone was
really interested in meeting him,
but since Fujimoto didn't
show interest in any of them,
they eventually all stopped
trying to be friends with him.
Even at school, it didn't seem like Fujimoto had any friends.
He gave off an aura of "don't come close to me", so perhaps that was unavoidable.
Welcome back!
Why don't you try telling her "I'm home"!
I don't like Kiyokazu.
Me neither.
Bye bye, Miss Sayaka!
Bye bye! See you tomorrow!
Kiyokazu... do you like the organ?
Kiyokazu!
Bye bye, Miss Sayaka! See you tomorrow!
Let's go!
Hurry up!
Fujimoto...
New Product!
F R E E
Have a Taste Campaign
Delicious cold beer!
Try some for free today!
Can I get one?
Here you go!
Would anyone like a delicious beer?
Special promotion!
May I have one of these please?
Y-Yes. It's a new product.
Please try some.
Thank you!
I'm sure Shuichiro will love it.
On a summer day like today,
when the weather was so beautiful...
It's my turn next!
No, I'm next!
You just went, didn't you?
Come now, no fighting.
Make sure everyone gets a turn.
Okay!
Will they bloom soon?
I'm sure they will.
I'm sure they'll bloom beautifully since
everyone's taking such good care of them.
Really?
Really.
Yay!
Now everyone, make sure you clean up first before going to play, okay?
Okay!
Welcome back.
Tomo, are you all right?
The ball suddenly flew over and
surprised her, that's why she fell!
Miss Sayaka!
Does it hurt anywhere? Are you okay?
What're you pushing for?
My bad.
I didn't think you'd actually fall.
Stop messing around!
I'm covered in dirt now.
Whatever, just hurry up and get the ball!
You're the one who missed the pass.
I got it, I got it.
Damn... Why is it so wet here?
Hey! What do you guys think you're doing?
Ah, our ball flew in here-
Don't you think playing like that is dangerous?
You just hit her with the ball!
We did not.
What're you so angry for?
Hurry up and get out of the garden!
What?
Everyone planted the sunflowers here
together and took really good care of them.
They're just about to bloom and everyone was really looking forward to it!
Here's your ball.
Apologize to this girl, to everyone, and then leave!
O-Our fault.
Sorry about that.
Your return was way too wide!
Then you shouldn't have passed me the ball there!
Miss Sayaka...
The sunflower...
It's okay. It just got a little hurt.
If we support it like this, and make sure we water it everyday,
I'm sure it'll still bloom.
You sure?
Yes.
Chase after the white, white clouds.
Run, run, with your friends by your side.
You can see everything,
from the top of the great mountains.
Search, keep searching...
For new wonders.
Did you know that Fujimoto is doing all sorts of part time work right now?
Yes.
PIzza delivery, bicycle repair,
newspaper delivery... and more.
So many?
Yes. He's working really hard to try and pay off even a little bit of the Nursery's debt.
For the Nursery?
Yes. He says he's going to become a lawyer.
He studies so late every night.
I'm afraid he's going to wreck his body.
They're so fluffy and smell so fresh!
The smell of sunshine.
Sunshine?
Yup.
Futons smell like sunshine after you air them out.
Or at least that's what my father used to say.
Then tomorrow everyone can
take a nap with Mr. Sunshine!
I guess they can.
D-Did I say something strange?
No, no, not at all. I think that's a beautiful idea.
Phew. Then I'm looking forward to tomorrow!
Let's take them down now.
Thank you for helping today. Get home safely, okay?
Okay! I'll see you tomorrow!
Mr. Sunshine, huh...
It's Kiyokazu!
Welcome back!
Could you play the organ again?
Please play!
Please!
It's Kiyokazu!
He's back!
Welcome back!
I... I'm home.
Kiyokazu, the organ, the organ!
Hurry, come on!
You can see the red, red sunset now.
Walk, walk, keep on walking steadily forward.
If it's sunny tomorrow,
come back over and play.
Time to go home, time to go home...
Home is right over there.
Look at that! You haven't
collected any more, have you?
But, but, I wanted to air out the futons and help out the Nursery!
You managed to air me out too!
I'm sorry...
Kobato? Ioryogi?
I knew it was you guys!
Perfect timing. I was just about to take this over.
C-Can I really have that?
Yup! I still have one for Shuichiro in the fridge.
All right, I'll take it!
Isn't that great, Ioryogi?
Okay, here I go! All in one gulp!
Actually wait! I'll restrain myself now so I can really enjoy it before bed.
You're always so careful about watering all of the greenery in the garden, Kohaku. It's beautiful!
This is about all I can do for Shuichiro.
I can only help a little, but being able to help him in any way makes me very happy.
Me too! If I can help out Yomogi
Nursery, it makes me really happy.
Being able to help out the people important to you is a great thing.
Important people...
The Nursery is really
important to Fujimoto, isn't it?
Yeah, even to the point where he's
doing multiple jobs to help support it.
I feel that way too.
The Nursery is really important to me too!
I'll work hard so I can help out Miss Sayaka and everyone too!
I'll do my best!
It seems like you're headed in the wrong direction again.
Welcome back, Kobato.
Welcome!
Welcome back!
I'm home.
Fujimoto!
Fujimoto, you were really cute when you were little!
And even though your legs were too short,
you did your best to play the organ, didn't you?
Why do you know that?!
Miss Sayaka showed me pictures today!
I want to see!
Me too!
I want to see little Fujimoto too.
Not you too, Chitose!
He was so little and cute, but still grumpy!
Stop talking right now!
We want to hear!
What should I do...
Let's wait till later when
Fujimoto isn't around.
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...Detective Kobato Hanato.